Sayantika Saha

Downtown, Kamloops, British Columbia

1250-879-7307

in

sayantika-saha-77ba61169

SUMMARY:

Experienced in operational and business analysis with a background in software engineering, and currently studying Applied Data Science. Proven in driving supply chain improvements through data-driven strategies. Certified in Google Data Analytics and IBM Data Science. Committed to student wellness and continuous learning.

SKILLS:

- Programming Languages: Python, R
- Data Visualization: Excel, Power BI, Tableau
- Web Programming: HTML, PHP, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JavaScript, Ajax, Laravel Framework
- **DBMS**: Oracle, MySQL
- IDE: Anaconda, Microsoft Visual Studio
- Operating System: Windows
 Version Control: GitHub, Docker
 https://github.com/Sayantika96

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Operation Analyst, Well Food & Beverage Company Ltd.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

November, 2022 - July, 2023

- 1. Gathered comprehensive supply chain data from various sources, including procurement, manufacturing, and distribution channels.
- 2. Identified and recommended strategic improvements resulting in a notable 5% increase in overall supply chain performance.

Business Analysis Intern, BRAC IT Services

Dhaka, Bangladesh

June, 2022 – September, 2022

- 1. Collaboratively designed and delivered user stories, optimizing and automating the pay system for clients, enhancing efficiency and accuracy.
- 2. Applied quantitative analysis and data visualization to minimize employee hiring time, resulting in a streamlined hiring process and improved operational efficiency.
- 3. Collaborated in a cross-functional team to meet data demands, applying quantitative methods to analyze data and contribute to enhanced decision-making processes.

Software Engineer, SUN CO, LTD, Japan

Dhaka, Bangladesh

May, 2020 - February, 2022

- 1. Developed a music school web system with secure payment options, streamlining enrollment and enhancing user experience.
- 2. Improved a Japanese language-learning app, allowing users to customize pricing and class duration for simplified and efficient deal-finding.
- 3. Communicated and documented effectively in both Japanese and English, contributing to successful project outcomes and client satisfaction.

**[completed Software engineering training under Kaicom Solutions Japan BD CO. LTD, which is a partner consultancy of SUN CO, LTD, from January, 2020 – March, 2020].]

Teletalk Bangladesh Limited [Industrial Trainee]

Dhaka, Bangladesh

March, 2019 – *May*, 2019

1. Handling the IT policies in the Department of IT & Billing.

American International University Bangladesh [Lab Assistant]

Dhaka, Bangladesh

October, 2018 – *December*, 2018

1. Assist the course teacher and provide services to the students inside Computer Networks laboratory class and additional duties assigned by the supervisor.

EDUCATION:

Thompson Rivers University

*Kamloops, British Columbia, Canada*Post-baccalaureate Diploma in Applied Data Science

September, 2023 – Present

American International University - Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Graduated in Computer Science and Engineering

June, 2015 – December, 2018

CERTIFICATIONS: (All the certificates can be found here)

- Deep Learning AI Supervised Machine Learning
- Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate
- IBM Data Science Professional Certificate
- Japanese Language Proficiency Test (Level N3)

PROJECTS: (All the projects can be found here)

- Enhancing Mental Health Surveillance
- FineTune-Phi-2-LLM-using-PEFT-QLora
- New York Air Bnb Data Analysis

- Analyzing Migration Trends in Canada
- Sales Data Analysis

PUBLICATION:

Sayantika, S. Shivani, T., Dhruv, A., et al. (2024). Investigating the Transformative Impact
of Generative AI on Academic Integrity Across Diverse Educational Domains. In *2nd
International Conference on Advancement in Computation & Computer Technologies IEEE*

LANGUAGES:

- 1. Bengali (Native)
- 2. English (Fluent)
- 3. Hindi (Fluent)
- 4. Japanese (Level: N3)
- 5. French (Level: A2)

EXTRA-CURRICULAR:

- 1. Social Media Coordinator at TRUSU Data Science Club
- 2. Volunteer at TRUSU French Club

REFERENCES:

Dr. Ajay Dhruv	Jeffery Hawker
Assistant Teaching Professor	Team Leader
Faculty of Science	Global Division
Thompson Rivers University	SUN CO, LTD
Email: adhruv@tru.ca	Email: j hawker@sun21.co.jp
	Phone: +81 80 3630 8060